<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>biodiversity on</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/tags/biodiversity/</link><description>Recent content in biodiversity on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://sethmb.xyz/tags/biodiversity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Biodiversity Overview</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Biodiversity/BiodiversityOverview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Biodiversity/BiodiversityOverview/</guid><description>What is biodiversity? Variety of organisms present in an area Species: a group of organisms with a very similar appearance, anatomy, physiology, biochemistry and genetics.</description></item><item><title>Factors affecting biodiversity</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Biodiversity/FactorsAffectingBiodiversity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Biodiversity/FactorsAffectingBiodiversity/</guid><description>Factors affecting biodiversity Deforestation: reduces the number of trees which in turn reduces the number of animals due to habitat and food loss.</description></item><item><title>Genetic Biodiversity</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Biodiversity/GeneticBiodiversity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Biodiversity/GeneticBiodiversity/</guid><description>alleles - different versions of the same gene genetic diversity—number of different alleles that exist in a species species with a greater genetic diversity will better adapt to their environment and be more resistant to to environmental change and therefore less likely to become extinct Factors affecting genetic biodiversity to increase biodiversity the number of alleles within a species must increase.</description></item><item><title>Maintaining Biodiversity</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Biodiversity/MaintainingBiodiversity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Biodiversity/MaintainingBiodiversity/</guid><description>Conservation, preservation and management of the environment and natural resources Two types: In situ Ex situ In-situ maintains genetic diversity and ability to adapt preserves interdependent relationships cheaper eg wildlife reserves, marine conservation zones Ex-situ normally used in conjunction with in-situ measures eg, botanical gardens, seed banks, captive breeding programs Conservation Agreements International Union for Conservation of Nature Publishes conservation status of threatened animals (RED list) Establishment of CITES (Convention on Internal Trade of Endangered Species) regulates international trade of plant/animal specimens and their products The Rio Convention Convention of Biological Diversity—strategies for sustainable development United Nations framework convention on climate change - agreement to stabilise greenhouse gases.</description></item><item><title>Sampling</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Biodiversity/Sampling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Biodiversity/Sampling/</guid><description>We use sampling to gain insight into organisms in an area. Sampling is taking measurements of a limited number of organisms present within an area.</description></item><item><title>Simpson's Diversity</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Biodiversity/SimpsonsDiversity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Biodiversity/SimpsonsDiversity/</guid><description>Measure of diversity in a habitat
Accounts for species richness and eveness
n = number of individuals of each species</description></item></channel></rss>