<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>business on</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/tags/business/</link><description>Recent content in business on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://sethmb.xyz/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Case Study: Perfect Paper Plc</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/3.2/CaseStudyPerfectPaper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/3.2/CaseStudyPerfectPaper/</guid><description>With reference to the Tannenbaum Schmidt continuum and Blake Mouton Grid, analyze what type of manager Jayne is. (9m) Jayne has received instructions from her superiors and has made a decision to remedy the situation.</description></item><item><title>Leadership or Management?</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/3.2/LeadershipOrManagement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/3.2/LeadershipOrManagement/</guid><description>Leaders: Inspire people, build relationships, take risks and have followers.
Managers: Enact the plan, use their authority, manage risks, have subordinates</description></item><item><title>Management and Leadership</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/3.2/ManagementAndLeadership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/3.2/ManagementAndLeadership/</guid><description>Leadership: A relationship through which one person influences the behaviour and actions of other people.
Leadership Skills Confidence (Laissez-faire) Perserverance Decisive Caring (Paternalistic) Discipline (Authoirtarian) Intelligence (EQ/IQ) And many others Different kinds of leader (leadership styles) will show different leadership skills to complement their style.</description></item><item><title>Management and Leadership Styles</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/3.2/LeadershipStyles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/3.2/LeadershipStyles/</guid><description>Authoritarian: Absolute power to the boss, gives orders, does not delegate responsibility. Frequently used in highly regulated industries, low skilled jobs and areas where there is no time for debate (military, emergency services etc).</description></item><item><title>What Is A Business?</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/3.1/WhatIsABusiness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/3.1/WhatIsABusiness/</guid><description>Definitions A business is an organisation that exists to provide goods and services on a commercial basis to customers.
Goods are physical products that can be traded.</description></item><item><title>What Is A Startup?</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/3.1/WhatIsAStartUp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/3.1/WhatIsAStartUp/</guid><description>Key Term: A start-up is a new business enterprise, formed by one or more entrepreneurs.
Entrepreneur:
A catalyst for the creation and grwoth of a business fulfill their dreams calculated risk taker organise all the resources find and fill gaps in the market Case Study: Olio An app that deals with improving waste management in the modern world.</description></item></channel></rss>