<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>business on</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/tags/business/</link><description>Recent content in business on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://sethmb.xyz/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Business Objectives</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/fh/BusinessObjectives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/fh/BusinessObjectives/</guid><description>![[content/sixth/Business/Units/fh/img/Pasted image 20220914095046.png]] The hierarchy of objectives
SMART - acronym helps management set effective objectives
S - Specific; the objective should state exactly what is to be achieved.</description></item><item><title>Case Study: Perfect Paper Plc</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/nd/CaseStudyPerfectPaper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/nd/CaseStudyPerfectPaper/</guid><description>With reference to the Tannenbaum Schmidt continuum and Blake Mouton Grid, analyze what type of manager Jayne is. (9m) Jayne has received instructions from her superiors and has made a decision to remedy the situation.</description></item><item><title>Case Study: Stakeholders</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/nd/CaseStudyStakeholders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/nd/CaseStudyStakeholders/</guid><description>The local community would stand to benefit from Roxio&amp;rsquo;s offerings. The availability of food, clothing, electronics and other basic items would improve the quality of life in the local area.</description></item><item><title>Case Study: Staying Private</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/fh/CaseStudyStayingPrivate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/fh/CaseStudyStayingPrivate/</guid><description>Timpson is a successful business with assets worth a lot of money. This makes them vulnerable to the impacts of having unlimited liability, as William Timpson and any other shareholders could be liable for any damages or debts that the company becomes involved in.</description></item><item><title>Decision Making</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/nd/DecisionMaking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/nd/DecisionMaking/</guid><description>Opportunity Cost: The cost of missing out on the next best alternative. The benefits that could have been gained by making a different decision.</description></item><item><title>Forms of Business Organisation</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/fh/BusinessOrganisation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/fh/BusinessOrganisation/</guid><description>Worksheet Shareholder -&amp;gt; Someone who invests capital in exchange for a part ownership in the company
Mutual -&amp;gt; A business jointly owned by all of its members and existing for the benefit of its members rather than making a profit</description></item><item><title>Leadership or Management?</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/nd/LeadershipOrManagement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/nd/LeadershipOrManagement/</guid><description>Leaders: Inspire people, build relationships, take risks and have followers.
Managers: Enact the plan, use their authority, manage risks, have subordinates</description></item><item><title>Management and Leadership</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/nd/ManagementAndLeadership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/nd/ManagementAndLeadership/</guid><description>Leadership: A relationship through which one person influences the behaviour and actions of other people.
Leadership Skills Confidence (Laissez-faire) Perserverance Decisive Caring (Paternalistic) Discipline (Authoirtarian) Intelligence (EQ/IQ) And many others Different kinds of leader (leadership styles) will show different leadership skills to complement their style.</description></item><item><title>Management and Leadership Styles</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/nd/LeadershipStyles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/nd/LeadershipStyles/</guid><description>Authoritarian: Absolute power to the boss, gives orders, does not delegate responsibility. Frequently used in highly regulated industries, low skilled jobs and areas where there is no time for debate (military, emergency services etc).</description></item><item><title>Public Sector Organisations</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/fh/PublicSector/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/fh/PublicSector/</guid><description>Public sector companies are a relatively small number of companies owned or controlled by the government.
Examples: RBS (Royal Bank of Scotland) (nationalized), Network Rail.</description></item><item><title>Stakeholders</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/nd/Stakeholders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/nd/Stakeholders/</guid><description>A stakeholder is anybody with an interest in the business.
Starbucks Stakeholders:
Employees Shareholders Customers Government Suppliers Local community Competitors Pressure groups Charities Stakeholders can be categorized as either internal or external.</description></item><item><title>To understand the measurement and importance of profit</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/fh/ProfitMeasurement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/fh/ProfitMeasurement/</guid><description>Pricing considerations Setting a price is very important, but can be difficult. The following need to be considered:
Profit margins Costs involved Competition Target market Type of product Inflation Brand image Quality Revenue and Price Revenue—total sales * price of product</description></item><item><title>Understanding Different Business Forms</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/fh/DifferentFormsOfBusiness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/fh/DifferentFormsOfBusiness/</guid><description>Business forms typically depend upon some of the following factors:
Business Objectives Stakeholders Shares &amp;amp; Shareholders Organisational structure Business Form Mapping The private sector is any business that is owned by partners, owners or shareholders.</description></item><item><title>What Is A Business?</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/fh/WhatIsABusiness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/fh/WhatIsABusiness/</guid><description>Definitions A business is an organisation that exists to provide goods and services on a commercial basis to customers.
Goods are physical products that can be traded.</description></item><item><title>What Is A Startup?</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/fh/WhatIsAStartUp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Business/Units/fh/WhatIsAStartUp/</guid><description>Key Term: A start-up is a new business enterprise, formed by one or more entrepreneurs.
Entrepreneur:
A catalyst for the creation and grwoth of a business fulfill their dreams calculated risk taker organise all the resources find and fill gaps in the market Case Study: Olio An app that deals with improving waste management in the modern world.</description></item></channel></rss>