<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>enzymes on</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/tags/enzymes/</link><description>Recent content in enzymes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://sethmb.xyz/tags/enzymes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Effectors</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Enzymes/Effectors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Enzymes/Effectors/</guid><description>Effect of Temperature Increasing temperature increase rate of reaction Particles move faster and are therefore more likely to collide Temperature coefficient, Q10 = how much the rate of reaction increases with a 10℃ rise.</description></item><item><title>Enzyme Reactions</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Enzymes/EnzymeReactions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Enzymes/EnzymeReactions/</guid><description>Intracellular/Extracellular enzymes Extracellular enzymes Released from cells Used to digest food Required to use polymers for nutrition Single-celled organisms release extracellular enzymes into their immediate environment Intracellular enzymes Act within cells Synthesis of polymers from monomers Destroy toxins such as hydrogen peroxide Digestion reactions Digestion of Starch Starch polymers are broken down into maltose (disaccharide) by amylase from pancreas and salivary glands Maltose broken into glucose by maltase in small intestines Glucose absorbed into blood Digestion of Proteins Trypsin is a form of protease Catalyses proteins -&amp;gt; smaller peptides Main reaction types Anabolic Reactions Building up reactions Combining two reactants into one product Protein synthesis Catabolic Reactions Breaking down Food digestion Breaking one reactant into two products Biology</description></item><item><title>Enzymes</title><link>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Enzymes/Enzymes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sethmb.xyz/sixth/Biology/Enzymes/Enzymes/</guid><description>What are enzymes? Biological catalysts Inside cells protein/lipid synthesis intercellular Outside cells digestion extracellular Globular proteins Generally soluble in water Functions Speed up a reaction Help build a larger molecule Help breakdown a large molecule into multiple smaller ones Activation energy Amount of energy which needs to be supplied for a reaction to proceed.</description></item></channel></rss>